Guide to the Louis H. Roddis Papers, 1823-1990 RL.01102
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Louis H. Roddis papers
1823-1990
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Roddis, Louis H. (Louis Harry), 1918-
RL.01102
50 Linear Feet
159.4 linear feet 95,000 Items
Collection reflects career of Louis H. Roddis in the general field of energy with emphasis on policy and strategic issues. Topics include electric power, gas resources, petroleum, water power, energy conservation, the energy crisis of the 1970s, nuclear power, and alternative energy sources. Primarily documented in the collection are developments with nuclear power and within the nuclear industry including materials related to the Chernobyl and Three Mile Island accidents. The collection also reflects Roddis' participation in a variety of public service, charitable, industrial, and trade organizations.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Louis H. (Louis Harry) Roddis Papers were donated to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library by Louis H. and Alice Roddis in 1982, 1984, 1991, and 1992. Processing of this collection was supported in part by gifts from Louis H. Roddis.
Biographical Note
Missing Title
1918, Sept. 9 Born in Charleston, S.C.
1935-1939 Received B.S. from U. S. Naval Academy
1939-1955 Officer on Active Duty in the United States Navy
1942-1944 Received M.S. in Naval Architecture and Marine Engineering from Massachusetts Institute of Technology
1946-1947 Attended Post-Doctorate Level Classified Training Course in Nuclear Reactors, Clinton Laboratories of the Manhattan Engineering District, now Oak Ridge National Laboratory
1946-1947 Worked at Project Officer in the Navy Nuclear Program for the Development of the Nuclear Power submarines, the Nautilus and the Sea Wolf
1947-1955 Assisted Nuclear Reactor Design U.S.S. Nautilus, Department of Navy
1955-1958 Deputy Director of Division of Reactor Development, Atomic Energy Commission
1957 Director of Nuclear Activities at the General Public Utilities Organization (later Service Company and the GPU Nuclear Corporation)
1958-1967 President and CEO of Pennsylvania Electric Company, Subsidiary of General Public Utilities (GPU), Johnstown, Pa.
1959-1969 Board Chairman, CEO, and Director of the Saxton Nuclear Experimental Corporation, a Subsidiary of GPU
1967-1969 Chairman of Pennsylvania Electric Company, Director of Nuclear Power Activities at General Public Utilities Corporation, New York City
1969-1973 President of Consolidated Edison
1973-1974 Vice Chairman of Consolidated Edison
1974-1975 Worked as Consultant to the Adminstrator of the U. S. Federal Energy Administration
1975-1976 President and CEO of John J. McMullen Associates
1976- Private Consulting Engineer
1991, Sept. 15 Died, Charleston, S.C.
Collection Overview
The Louis H. (Louis Harry) Roddis Papers span the years 1823 to 1990 with the bulk of the materials dating from the 1970s and 1980s. The collection reflects Roddis's distinguished career in the general field of energy with emphasis on policy and strategic issues. Topics include electric power, gas resources, petroleum, water power, energy conservation, the energy crisis of the 1970s, and alternative energy sources. Primarily documented in the collection are developments with nuclear power and within the nuclear industry. The collection also reflects Roddis's participation in a variety of public service, charitable, industrial, and trade organizations. Materials in the collection include reports, speeches, testimonies, rebuttals, annual reports, articles, clippings, studies, photographs, meeting minutes and agendas, memoranda, legal briefs, writings, and printed materials. The collection documents his involvement with the US government on various energy issues, Roddis's interest in the human safety aspect of the energy industry, his professional interests in utility companies of which he was a board member, and his private work as a consulting engineer. Correspondents include US government agencies, US and international utility company executives, and colleagues from professional organizations. US government agencies and committees represented in the collection include the Department of Energy, the Energy Research Advisory Board, the Atomic Industrial Forum, the Federal Energy Administration, the Atomic Energy Commission, and the Energy Research and Development Administration.
The series in the Roddis papers document following broad topics: energy sources and alternatives, nuclear energy, issues of utility companies, US energy policies, professional and government energy organizations, and Roddis's work as a consulting engineer and authority in the energy field.
Energy sources and alternatives are topics included in the following series: Fossil Energy; Solar Energy; Oceans and Policy; Energy Conservation; Energy Sources; and Transportation Energy.
Series which pertain to nuclear energy include Atomic Energy History; Fast Breeder Reactors; Nuclear Power Industry; Environmental Radioactivity; Nuclear Fuel Cycle; Waste Disposal and Proliferation; Floating Nuclear Ship Power / PropulsionPlants; Nuclear Power Plant Siting; Three Mile Island Accident; Human Factors; and Chernobyl.
The US Utility History; Consolidated Edison History; International Utilities; US Utility Rates and Financing; Transmission and Distribution; Detroit Edison; Puerto Rico Electric Power Authority; Puerto Rico Water Resource Authority; Long Island Lighting Company; and Washington Public Power Supply series relate to key issues for utility companies.
The Energy Policy; Energy Statistics; Science and Technology Policy; and Energy and the Environment series cover US energy policies.
Professional and government energy organizations represented in the collection are found in the following series: Institute of Nuclear Power Operations; Committee on Nuclear and Alternative Energy Systems; Energy Research and Development Administration; Energy Research and Development Planning; Energy Research Advisory Board (ERAB); Panel and Committee Reports of ERAB; Other Government Agencies Material; Other; Electric Power Research Institute; Atomic Industrial Forum; North American Electric Reliability Council; Edison Electric Institute; Committees and Panels; Gas Research; and Renewable Energy Institute.
The Pacific Sierra; Anti-Trust Cases; International Nuclear Energy Systems Company; Exxon; J. V. Neely; Gould; Speeches; Donavan Hamester and Rattien; Contracts; John J. McMullen Associates; Berlin Energy Congress; Testimonies and Depositions; and Liquefied Natural Gas Imports seriesdocument Roddis's work as a consulting engineer and authority in the energy field.
The material in the Miscellaneous Series overlaps with other series found throughout the collection. Topics include nuclear energy, the utility industry, professional organizations, marine energy, reports from power plants and utility companies such as the North Carolina Energy Corporation, energy conferences, and the U.S.S. Nautilus which Roddis was involved in designing.
Nuclear energy; Nuclear industry; Energy policy; Photographs; Energy conservation -- United States; Natural gas; Electric power; Water-power; Speeches; Natural resources; Petroleum; Clippings (information artifacts); Energy industries Safety measures United States; Industrial safety United States; Energy industries; Power resources; Chernobyl Nuclear Accident, Chornobylʹ, Ukraine, 1986; United States. Energy Research and Development Administration; United States. Energy Research Advisory Board; United States. Federal Energy Administration; Roddis, Louis H. (Louis Harry), 1918-; United States. Dept. of Energy; U.S. Atomic Energy Commission; Atomic Industrial Forum; Three Mile Island Nuclear Power Plant (Pa.)
- Atomic Energy History, 1973-1974, 1978, 1989, and undated
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes reports, speeches, press releases, notes, and testimonies about nuclear power plants, the development of reactors, and the evolving opinion of nuclear energy in the 1970s. Arranged by Roddis's index codes.
  - 1-66, An Independent Review of the Thermal Effects and Radioactive Releases from Nuclear Power Plants, 1989, Jan. (Box 1)
  - 1-89, American Nuclear Society Conference Program, Notes, and Copies of Speeches, 1978, Oct. 15-18 (Box 1)
  - 1-90, Nuclear Power Development, 1974, Dec. 17 (Box 1)
  - 1-99, Miscellaneous Papers:
    - Validating the Nuclear Option, remarks by Honorable John C. Sawmill, 1974, June 26 (Box 1)
    - Press Release: Sawhill Endorses Nuclear Power Development, 1974, June 26 (Box 1)
    - Energy Needs, Nuclear Power and the Environment, by Alvin M. Weinberg, 1974, July 15 (Box 1)
    - Joint Committee on Atomic Energy, Testimony of Jerome S. Katzin, 1974, July 16 (Box 1)
    - Northeast Utilities System AEC Regulatory Effects on Cost and Schedule of Nuclear Power Stations, 1973, Dec. 6 (Box 1)
  - 1-101, The Argone Family Tree, Past and Present, undated (Box 1)
- U.S. Utility History, 1972, 1974, 1982
  Comprised of a speech discussing the complex phases of the energy issue, a bibliography of the American Gas Association Library's major sources, and a study proposal on the ability of the utility industry to supply electrical needs for the nation. Arranged by Roddis's index codes.
  - 2-63, The Indispensability of Research, by Philip Sporn, 1972, Dec. 11 (Box 1)
  - 2-69, History of the American Gas Industry Bibliography, 1974 (Box 1)
  - 24-2-5, A Proposed Study on Institutional Structures of the U.S. Electric Power Industry, by George C. White and George Dummer, 1982, Mar. (Box 1)
- Consolidated Edison History, 1823-1962, 1965-1990 (bulk 1970-1975)
  Materials include articles, reports, booklets, press releases, annual reports, correspondence, circulars specially bound, and items collected during Roddis'ss employment at Consolidated Edison (Con Edison). Specific topics include Con Edison lawsuits, long range planning, power failures and investigations to prevent blackouts, stockholders and board members' packets containing meetings agendas, quarterly financial and operating reports, meeting minutes, and financial statistics. Also includes Roddis's correspondence files from his service as President and Vice Chairman. Arranged by Roddis's index codes.
  - 3-15, Con Edison Articles and Circulars, Volume 1, 1896, 1898, 1936, 1940, 1955, 1966, 1969, 1973 (volume) (Box 1)
  - 3-16, Con Edison Articles and Circulars, Volume 2, 1923, 1930, 1951, 1953, 1962, 1964-1969, 1972-1973 and undated (volume) (Box 1)
  - 3-17, Con Edison Articles and Circulars, Volume 3, 1969-1975, 1978, 1981, and undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 3-18, A Review of Earnings, Dividends, and Market Prices, 1972, July 12 (Box 1)
  - 3-19, Con Edison Revised Schedule for the Retention of Company Records, 1973 (Box 1)
  - 3-20, Con Edison Mobile Equipment, 1970, Feb. (volume) (Box 1)
  - Consolidated Gas Company of New York--A History, 1934 Nov. (Box 2)
  - 3-21, Origins of the Consolidated Gas Company of New York, 1823-1884 (volume) (Box 2)
  - 3-22, History of Brooklyn Edison 1883-1932, History of Con Edison 1823-1957" (volume) (Box 2)
  - 3-23, Con Edison System: Corporate History, 1930-1962 (volume) (Box 2)
  - 3-24, A Power History of the Consolidated Edison System, 1878-1900, by Patyson Jones, 1940 (volume) (Box 2)
  - 3-26, Con Edison Engineering Orientation Courses, 1969 (volume) (Box 2)
  - 3-27, Con Edison: Cornwall, 1962-1973 (volume) (Box 2)
  - 3-30, Con Edison Organization, August 1967, 1967-1969 (volume) (Box 2)
  - 3-31, Con Edison Bazeley Committee Report on Reorganization Volume 1 and 2, 1969, March (volume) (Box 3)
  - 3-32, Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc, Survey of the Organization, 1968, June (volume) (Box 3)
  - 3-33, Comments of consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc. on Arthur D. Little, Inc. Report on Con Edison, 1975, March (volume) (Box 3)
  - 3-34, Con Edison Management and Operations Study for New York (Box 3)
  - State Public Service Commission, by Arthur D. Little, Inc., 1975, March (volume) (Box 3)
  - 3-36, Con Edison Long Range Planning, Volume 1, 1966-1972 (volume) (Box 3)
  - 3-37, Con Edison Long Range Planning, Volume 2, 1966-1972 (volume) (Box 3)
  - 3-38, Con Edison Long Range Planning, Volume 3, 1966-1972 (volume) (Box 3)
  - 3-39, Con Edison Long Range Planning, Volume 4, 1966-1972 (volume) (Box 4)
  - 3-40, Con Edison Long Range Planning, Volume 5, 1966-1972 (volume) (Box 4)
  - 3-54, Northeast Power Failure, 1965, Volume 1, 1965, 1967, and undated (volume) (Box 4)
  - 3-55, Northeast Power Failure, 1965, Volume 2, 1965-1967, and undated (volume) (Box 4)
  - 3-56, Northeast Power Failure, 1965, Volume 3, 1965 and undated (volume) (Box 4)
  - 3-57, Northeast Power Failure, 1965, Volume 4, 1965-1967 (volume) (Box 4)
  - Consolidated Edison Annual Reports, 1969-1974 (Box 4)
  - Consolidated Gas Company of New York--A History, 1934 Nov. (Box 4)
  - 3-59, Con Edison Brooklyn-Queens Network Outages, 1972-1973, (volume) (Box 5)
  - 3-60, Con Edison Blackout of July 13-14, 1977, 1977-1979 (Box 5)
  - 3-71, Con Edison Blackout Investigation Statement and Report, 1977, July-Aug. (Box 5)
  - 3-72, The Events Leading to the Consolidated Edison Company Blackout of July 13, 1977, 1977 Sept. 15 (Box 5)
  - 3-73, Order Directing Short-Term Measures to Improve System Reliability, New York State Public Service Commission, 1978 (Box 5)
  - 3-90, Information and Data for Stockholders Meeting of May 17, 1971, 1971 May (Box 5)
  - 3-92, Information and Data for Stockholders Meeting of May 21, 1973, 1973, May, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 3-93, Information and Data for Stockholders Meeting of May 20, 1974, 1974, May, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 3-94, Con Edison Board Package, 1973, Aug., 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 3-95, Con Edison Board Package, 1973, Sept., 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 3-96, Con Edison Board Package, 1973, Oct., 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 3-97, Con Edison Board Package, 1973, Nov., 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 3-98, Con Edison Board Package, 1973, Dec., 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 3-99, Con Edison Board Package, 1974, Jan., 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 3-100, Con Edison Board Package, 1974, Feb., 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 3-101, Con Edison Board Package, 1974, March, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 3-102, Con Edison Board Package, 1974, April, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 3-103, Con Edison Board Package, 1974, May, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 3-104, Con Edison Board Package, 1974, June, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 3-105, Con Edison Board Package, 1974, July, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 3-106, Con Edison Board Package, 1974, Aug., 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 3-107, Con Edison Board Package, 1974, Sept., 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 3-108, Con Edison Board Package, 1974, Oct., 2 folders (Box 6)
  - 3-109, Con Edison Budget and Contracts Committee meeting, 1973, Dec. 10 (Box 7)
  - 3-110, Con Edison Audit Committee meeting, 1973, Nov. 27 (Box 7)
  - 3-111, Gas System Sale Memorandum, 1974, Sept. 4 (Box 7)
  - 3-112, Con Edison Operating Statistics Yearbook and Inserts, 1972, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - 3-113, Electric Service Reports, 1965-1972, 4 folders (Box 7)
  - 3-114, Daylight Savings Time, 1973 (Box 7)
  - 3-114, Overtime, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - 3-114, Con Edison Lawsuits, 1974 and 1979 (Box 7)
  - 3-114, Questionnaire and Agreements, 1970, 1972-1974 (Box 7)
  - 3-114, Incentive Compensation, 1970 (Box 7)
  - 3-114, Combined Cycles, 1970 (Box 7)
  - 3-115, Book Cost of Utility Plant, 1972, Dec. 31 (Box 7)
  - 3-115, Analysis of Security holders as of Dec. 31, 1972, 1972 (Box 7)
  - 3-115, Responsibility Report, 1973, Dec. (Box 7)
  - 3-115, Responsibility Report, 1974, Dec. (Box 7)
  - 3-115, Division Income Statements and Operating Statistics, 1973, Oct. (Box 7)
  - 3-115, Gas Financial and Statistical Report, 1974, Aug. (Box 7)
  - 3-116, Daily office notes, messages, press releases, and clippings, 1974, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - 3-117, Recommendations on Cost Reductions, 1971, 1973-1974, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - 3-118, Board Practices, 1974, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - 3-118, Directors and Officers Liability, 1969-1971, 1973 (Box 7)
  - 3-119, Consolidated Edison v. Shapiro et. al. Lawsuit, 1975-1976, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - 3-120, Con Edison v. Atomic Energy Commission, 1975-1977, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - 3-121, Con Edison v. Atomic Energy Commission, 1975, 1977, 5 folders (Box 8)
  - 3-122, Louis H. Roddis Correspondence, 1970 Jan. 15-1970 Dec. 18, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - 3-123, Louis H. Roddis Correspondence, 1971 Jan. 5-1971 Dec. 28, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - 3-124, Louis H. Roddis Correspondence, 1972 Jan. 6-1972 Dec. 26, 4 folders (Box 8)
  - 3-124, Louis H. Roddis Correspondence, 1972 Jan. 6-1972 Dec. 26, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - 3-125, Louis H. Roddis Correspondence, 1973 Jan. 3-1973 June 11, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - 3-126, Louis H. Roddis Correspondence, 1973 July 2-1973 Dec. 26, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - 3-127, Louis H. Roddis Correspondence, 1974 Jan. 2-1974 June 28, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - 3-128, Louis H. Roddis Correspondence, 1974 July 1-1974 Dec. 24, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - 3-130, Con Edison Capital Expenditure estimates and reports, 1973-1982, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - 3-134, Con Edison Miscellaneous Items, 1971-1990 (Box 9)
  - 3-136, Plant Outages, 1970-1972 (Box 9)
  - Articles on Con Edison's financial and operating problems, 1974, and n..d. (Box 9)
- Energy Policy, 1969-1982 and undated (bulk 1973-1976)
  Contains speeches, writings, reports, press kits, articles, booklets, writings, studies, charts, graphs, clippings, press releases, and circulars relating to the United States energy policies. Materials discuss energy resources, clean energy, presidential programs and stands on energy issues, and the need to practice conservation and to locate new energy supplies. Also covered are possible energy futures and ways to make these futures happen, assessments of the US and World energy situation and outlook, consumption patterns, gas technologies, evolution of nuclear power, international cooperation on nuclear power, problems and prospects of nuclear power. Includes a speech by Roddis and statements by United States Presidents on energy issues and President Ford's January 1975 State of the Union Address. Arranged by Roddis's index codes.
  - 4-31, Energy Resources Forum Speeches, including Louis H. Roddis, 1974, June 7 (Box 9)
  - 4-52, A Position Paper, A Strategy for Energy Research and Development, by Alvin M. Weinburg and Calvin C. Burwell, 1973, Sept. - Oct. (Box 9)
  - 4-56, Committee on Public Engineering Policy Report on Alternative strategies for the effective utilization of (RANN's) applied research results preliminary draft, 1975, Jan. 10 (Box 9)
  - 4-82, Public releases on A Time to Choose, the final report of the energy policy project, 1974 (Box 9)
  - 4-107, Energy Resources Forum, Press Kit, 1974, June 7 (Box 9)
  - 4-108, U.S. National Committee, World Energy Conference, Information Booklet, 1972 (Box 9)
  - 4-147, Committee for Economic Development policy statement Achieving Energy Independence galley and press releases, 1974, Dec. 9 (Box 10)
  - 4-165, Energy Crisis, a collection of various materials, Volume I, 1972-1973, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - 4-166, Energy Crisis, a collection of various materials, Volume II, 1973-1975, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - 4-167, Energy Crisis, a collection of various materials, Volume III, 1975-1976, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - 4-168, Energy Crisis, a collection of various materials, Volume IV, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
  - 4-169, President Nixon's Energy Message, 1971-1974, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - 4-170, Papers on the President's Program, 1975 (Box 10)
  - 4-171, Energy Forecasts, 1972-1978 (Box 10)
  - 4-173, General Facts on Energy, 1969-1974 and undated, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - 4-174, Speeches by W. Kenneth Davis, 1979-1982 (Box 10)
  - 4-175, Speeches by Henry Linden, 1977-1981 (Box 11)
  - 4-176, United States President's State of the Union and Energy Speeches 1974-1975, 1979 and undated, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - 4-211, Project Independence Press Kit, Staff of Federal Energy Administration, 1974, Nov. 12 (Box 11)
  - 4-212, Research and Development in Project Independence Press Kit, 1974, Nov. 12 (Box 11)
  - 4-213, Energy Policy Options Debated at ERC seminars on Project Independence, 1974, Dec. 9-11 (Box 11)
  - 4-221, Energy Issues, 1977, 1979-1981 and undated (Box 11)
  - 24-4-232, Speech by Donald M. Alstadt, Human Knowledge, the Legalistic Mentality and National Survival, 1975, Oct. 29 (Box 11)
  - 24-4-242, Speech by Chalmer G. Kirkbride, The Energy Famine of 1976 to 1985, Wake up America! 1976, Nov. (Box 11)
  - 24-4-243, Atomic Industrial Forum, Inc. and Carter-Mondale transition team Correspondence, 1976, Dec. (Box 11)
  - 24-4-244, Miscellaneous, 1976 and undated (Box 11)
- Energy Statistics, 1971-1975, 1982
  Consists of annual reports, press releases, and reports on comparative statistical data of consumers, sales, expenditures, and future needs of utility companies in the Northeast and the Great Lakes area. Arranged by Roddis's index codes.
  - 5-53, State of New York Public Service Commission Annual Report, and inserts, 1972-1974 (Box 11)
  - 5-54, Intercompany Performance Comparison Group Annual Report, 1973 (Box 11)
  - 5-56, Comparative Financial Data, Fifty Largest Utility Companies, 1971 (Box 11)
  - 5-80, Federal Power Commission News Release, 1973, Nov. 2 (Box 11)
  - 5-111, Energy Efficiency of the Future, 1975, 1982 (Box 11)
- Energy and the Environment, 1967-1979, 1981-1984
  Comprised of articles, pamphlets, reports, speeches, writings, and booklets pertaining to energy and its various effects on the environment, human and economic consumption of energy, the effects of energy emissions waste, and discusses the conflict between the human consumption of energy and the effects it has on the environment. Arranged by Roddis's index codes.
  - 6-12, Energy in the City Environment, 1972, May 18 (Box 11)
  - 6-16, Environmental Assessments of Alternative Energy Strategies in the United States, 1979, Nov. (Box 11)
  - 6-33, Electric Energy and the Environment, Book I, 1967-1974, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - 6-34, Electric Energy and the Environment, Book II, 1974-1976, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - 6-53, Water, 1969-1974, 1981 and undated, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - 6-53, Water, 1969-1974, 1981 and undated (Box 12)
  - 6-72, Air, 1969-1970, 1972-1974, 1981, and undated, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - 6-73, Nitrogen Oxide Emissions, NOx, 1970-1973 (Box 12)
  - 6-74, Sulfur Oxide Emissions (SO2), 1970-1972, 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - 6-75, Trace Elements, 1970 (Box 12)
  - 24-6-76, Acid Rain, 1982-1983, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - 24-6-77, Radiation Monitoring, General Atomic Technologies, 1981-1984, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - 24-6-78, An Inventory of Numeric Data for Carbon Dioxide, 1984, June, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - 24-6-93, Application of the Risk/Benefit Approach to the Energy/Environment Conflict, 1978, Oct. 18 (Box 12)
  - 24-6-95, Miscellaneous, 1977, 1979, 1983-1984 (Box 12)
- Fast Breeder Reactors, 1969-1979, 1981-1982 and undated
  Includes correspondence, reports, articles, a presentation by Roddis before the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy, and correspondence and reports of the Atomic Industrial Forum's Breeder Policy Committee of which Roddis was a member. This series looks at different types of breeder reactors and the usage of nuclear energy to supply future projected energy needs.
  - 7-11, Assessment of the Demonstration Plant Principle Design Decisions, 1974, Jan. (Box 13)
  - 7-20, Light Water Breeder Reactor, 1969-1970, 1972, 1974, 1978, 1981 and undated, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - 7-21, Liquid Metal Fast Breeder, Volume I, 1967-1971, 1973-1976 and undated, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - 7-22, Liquid Metal Fast Breeder, Volume II, 1972, 1974, 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - 7-23, Atomic Industrial Forum Breeder Policy Committee Correspondence and Minutes, 1976-1979, 1 folder (Box 13)